Titouan Renard,

Master student in Robotics with a minor in Data Science

© (+41) 79 944 61 65

図 titouan.renard@epfl.ch 命 github.com/RenardDesNeiges

© Rue de la paix 9, 1020 Renens, Switzerland

I am a student at EPFL currently pursuing a Master of Sciences in Robotics with a minor in Data Science. As I have progressed in my master I realized that I have a interest in reasearch with focus in optimal control, reinforcement learning and learning theory (which are the topics I have mostly worked on).

Education

Ongoing Master in Robotics with a Minor in Data Science, Lausanne, Switzerland	2020-Present
EPFL, STI and IC faculties	
Bachelor in Microengineering, Lausanne, Switzerland	2020
EPFL, STI faculty	
Bilingual Maturité, Neuchâtel, Switzerland	2016
French-English bilingual high-school, Lycée Denis de Rougemont, Physics and Applied Math	

Past Projects

Learning Motor Policies with Time Continuous Neural Networks, semester project	2022
supervised by two labs, BIOROB (Biorobotics) and LCN (Laboratory of Computational	
Neuroscience) at EPFL, under ther supervision of Prof. Auke Ijspeert and Prof. Wulfram	
Gerstner. Project Graded 6/6	

Work on the use of time continuous neural networks (Liquid Time-Constant Neural Networks) to solve control problems using reinforcement learning methods.

Power-Optimal Trajectory Generation for Airborne Wind Energy, semester project at LA3	2021
(EPFL), under ther supervision of Prof. Colin Jones. Project graded 6/6.	

Worked on a strongly non-linear and non-convex optimization problem, implemented an appropriate iterative solver method to deal with the non-convexity in Matlab.

Deep Robust Navigation with Cognitive Mapping Visual Representations, project done in	2021
the "Visual Intelligence - Machines and Minds" course at (EPFL), course given by Prof. Amir	
Zamir.	

Development and implementation of a novel deep-reinfocement learning method for visual navigation. Presentation Video of the Project. Project graded 5.75/6.

Skills

Programming, in C, C++, Javascript, Matlab, Python and Scala. Experience with OpenCV, Scipy, CasAdi, Tensorflow, Jax and Pytorch, comfortable with Unix systems and git. Experience with Google Cloud Platform and with SLURM for training deep learning models.

Math and Applied Math, Probabilities, Linear Algebra, Calculus, Dynamic System Theory and Control Theory, Signal Processing, Algorithmic Design and Analysis. Strong abstraction capacity, ability to mathematically formulate a concrete problem.

Soft Skills, public speaking, writing and team management learned in the context student associations, French (native proficiency), English (full proficiency), German (B2)

Relevant Courses

Course	Grade
Networks out of Control (COM-512)	5.25/6
Visual Intelligence, Machines and Minds (CS-503)	5.75/6
Legged Robotics (MICRO-507)	5.75/6
Model Predictive Control (ME-425)	5.75/6
Algorithms (CS-250)	5.5/6
Advanced Algorithms (CS-450)	6/6
Artifical Neural Networks (CS-456)	5.75/6
Aerial Robotics (MICRO-502)	5/6
Computer Vision (CS-442)	5.5/6

Distributed Intelligent Systems (ENG-466) Analysis and Modelling of Locomotion (BIOENG-404) Functional Programming (CS-210)	5/6 5/6 5.5/6
Experience	
Internships Machine-Learning Intern at 3HLE Robotics and Automation Worked on deep-learning models for 6D pose estimation from rgbd sensor data in the context robotics maniplation.	2022-2023 of industrial
Summer Internship, at EPFL's Birorobotics Lab, under the supervision of Alessandro Crespi. Implementation of a simple vision-based localization system using C++ and OpenCV.	2018
Student-Assistant at EPFL Artifical Neural Networks	2022
For the Computer Science and Data Science students. "Physique Générale 1" (Newtonian Mechanics) For the PH-101(b) (Microengineering, Electrical Engineering and Material Sciences sections) and securing sections.	2018-2021 d PH-101(d)
courses (for the Mechanical Engineering section). "Microinformatique" (basics of embedded systems programming) For the Microsophic or at Industry.	2019
For the Microengineering students. Basics of Robotics	2018
For the Microengineering students. Material Sciences Practicals For the Microengineering and Material sciences students.	2018
Volunteer Experience	
Unipoly, student's association for sustainabily at EPFL.	2019-2022
Board member in an association of approximately 300 membres with a 20'000 CHF annual budget. Président Experience with team management and budgets.	2021-2022
Responsable Politique, Experience in interactions with stakeholders and EPFL's direction on matters of sustainabily on cam	2020-2021 npus.

Management and coordination of about 30 events (conferences, workshops) on EPFL and UNIL's campuses.

Writer for Unipoly's Journal

2015-2016

2019-2020

2019-2021

English language public speaking experience.

Responsible of Events for the 2020 sustainabily week on EPFL campus